David Andrianarivo

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

andrianarivo.david@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Wellfound | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Detail-oriented with a growth mindset and +5 years of industry experience. Eager to join the company to build creative solutions for their business. A Full-stack software developer using React and NodeJS/Rails that brings unique traits to the table: collaboration and leadership.

SKILLS

Front-End: Typescript, React, Redux, Android, iOS Back-End: NodeJS, Rails, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, CI/CD **Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Mob Programming

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full-stack Web Developer & Mentor

Remote March 2023 – Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building eight full-stack projects both independently and via pair programming.

<u>Restaurant Budgeter</u> — a mobile web application for budget management, featuring a transaction list categorized to help authenticated users track their spending.

• Built with: Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, SASS

BookStore — a book library app which helps users keep track of their preferred books and authors.

• Built with: React, Redux, and CSS modules

MICROVERSE

Mentor (Volunteer)

Remote

- April 2023 Present

 Mentor (Volunteer)

 Mentored +10 junior web developers, providing technical support through Slack and Github.
- Improvements to code organization, code quality and overall performance by 15%.
- Provided advice and tips to +10 students to maintain longevity in the program.

FUTURMAP DATA

Android/iOS Tech Lead

Antananarivo, Madagascar October 2020 – July 2023

- Accomplished adhering to industry standards, as measured by a 20% increase in overall code quality and a 25% improvement in performance, through training and workshops.
- Accomplished the development of +5 high-quality mobile apps, as evidenced by a 10% overall increase in user retention, achieved through the implementation of extreme programming.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

March 2023 - December 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard Gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ISPM

Master's degree in Computer Science

December 2016 - December 2022

- Bachelor thesis: WAN monitoring using the SNMP protocol with Centreon.
- Master thesis: Augmented Reality and OpenGL on Android Applications.